<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sedentarisation on Abigail E. Page</title>
    <link>https://abbeyepage.com/tags/sedentarisation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sedentarisation on Abigail E. Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://abbeyepage.com/tags/sedentarisation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Page, A. E., et al. (2018) Hunter-gatherer health and development policy. Social Science and Medicine.</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/14health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/14health/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Page, A. E., Minter, T., Viguier, S., and Migliano, A. B. (2018) Hunter-gatherer health and development policy: how the promotion of sedentism worsens the Agta’s health outcomes. Social Science and Medicine, 197: 39-48.
Abstract
Many hunter-gatherer groups live on the outskirts of wider society, experiencing poor health outcomes with little access to medical care. From a development perspective, key interventions include the sedentarisation of these mobile peoples into camps nearby larger towns with sanitation infrastructure and medical care, as increased access to services is assumed to improve outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Page, A. E., et al. (2016) Reproductive trade-offs in extant hunter-gatherers suggest adaptive mechanism for the Neolithic expansion. PNAS</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/21tradeoff/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/21tradeoff/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Page, A. E., Viguier, S., Dyble, M., Smith, D., Chaudhary, N., Salali, G., Thompson, J., Vinicius, L., Mace, R., and Migliano, A. B. (2016) Reproductive trade-offs in extant hunter-gatherers suggest adaptive mechanism for the Neolithic expansion. PNAS, 113 (17): 4694-4699.
Abstract
The Neolithic demographic transition remains a paradox, because it is associated with both higher rates of population growth and increased morbidity and mortality rates. Here we reconcile the conflicting evidence by proposing that the spread of agriculture involved a life history quality–quantity trade-off whereby mothers traded offspring survival for increased fertility, achieving greater reproductive success despite deteriorating health.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
