<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Evolutionary ecology on Abigail E. Page</title>
    <link>https://abbeyepage.com/tags/evolutionary-ecology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Evolutionary ecology on Abigail E. Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://abbeyepage.com/tags/evolutionary-ecology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Emmott, E. H., Myers, S. and Page, A. E. (2021) Who cares for women with children? Phil Trans. B.</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/2editoral/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/2editoral/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Emmott, E. H., Myers, S. and Page, A. E. (2021) Who cares for women with children? Crossing the bridge between disciplines. Phil Trans. B&amp;hellip;..
Abstract
It has long been acknowledged that women with children require social support to promote their health and wellbeing, as well as that of their children. However, the dominant conceptualizations of support have been heavily influenced by Western family norms. The consequence, at best, has been to stifle our understanding of the nature and consequences of support for mothers and children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Myers, S., Page, A. E. and Emmott, E. H., (2021) The differential role of practical and emotional support in infant feeding experience in the UK? Phil Trans. B.</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/4infantfeeding/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/4infantfeeding/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Myers, S., Page, A. E. and Emmott, E. H., (2021) The differential role of practical and emotional support in infant feeding experience in the UK? Phil Trans. B&amp;hellip;..
Abstract
Social support is a known determinant of breastfeeding behaviour and is generally considered beneficial. However, social support encompasses a myriad of different supportive acts, providing scope for diverse infant feeding outcomes. Given the vulnerability of postpartum mental health, this paper aims to explore both how support prolongs breastfeeding and which forms of support promote the positive experience of all infant feeding.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
