<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Maternal-child health on Abigail E. Page</title>
    <link>https://abbeyepage.com/tags/maternal-child-health/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Maternal-child health on Abigail E. Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://abbeyepage.com/tags/maternal-child-health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Emmott, E. H., Myers, S. and Page, A. E. (2021) Who cares for women with children? Phil Trans. B.</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/2editoral/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/2editoral/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Emmott, E. H., Myers, S. and Page, A. E. (2021) Who cares for women with children? Crossing the bridge between disciplines. Phil Trans. B&amp;hellip;..
Abstract
It has long been acknowledged that women with children require social support to promote their health and wellbeing, as well as that of their children. However, the dominant conceptualizations of support have been heavily influenced by Western family norms. The consequence, at best, has been to stifle our understanding of the nature and consequences of support for mothers and children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multidisciplinary Perspectives on Social Support and Maternal Child Health: Guest edited issue of Phil. Trans. B.</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/3specialissue/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/3specialissue/</guid>
      <description>It is widely acknowledged that women with children require high levels of social support to promote their, and their children’s, health and wellbeing. However, studies on social support often take overly narrow Western perspectives, leading to biased understandings of support and its impact on maternal-child health. We know social support is complex, coming in different forms and from different sources, influenced by environmental context. In this multidisciplinary special issue, we explore social support from different perspectives: While Western norms assume that childcare comes under the responsibility of mothers, in reality, childrearing is widely shared and supported in different ways across societies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Myers, S., Page, A. E. and Emmott, E. H., (2021) The differential role of practical and emotional support in infant feeding experience in the UK? Phil Trans. B.</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/4infantfeeding/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/4infantfeeding/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Myers, S., Page, A. E. and Emmott, E. H., (2021) The differential role of practical and emotional support in infant feeding experience in the UK? Phil Trans. B&amp;hellip;..
Abstract
Social support is a known determinant of breastfeeding behaviour and is generally considered beneficial. However, social support encompasses a myriad of different supportive acts, providing scope for diverse infant feeding outcomes. Given the vulnerability of postpartum mental health, this paper aims to explore both how support prolongs breastfeeding and which forms of support promote the positive experience of all infant feeding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Page, A. E. et al. (2021) Children are important too. Phil Trans. B.</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/1playgroups/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/1playgroups/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Page, A. E., Emmott, E. H., Dyble, M., Smith, D., Chaudhary, N., Viguier, S., &amp;amp; Migliano, A. (2021) Children are important too: juvenile playgroups and maternal childcare in a foraging population, the Agta. Phil. Trans. R. Soc. B 376: 20200026.
Abstract
Non-maternal caregivers (allomothers) are hypothesised to lighten the mother’s workload, producing human’s specialised life history where multiple dependent offspring are produced over a relatively short time period. Here, using in-depth observational data on who for cares for 78 Agta children (aged 0-6 years, a foraging population in northern Philippines), we explore whether allomaternal childcare substitutes (and thus decreases) maternal childcare.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Page, A. E. et al. (2021) Children are important too. Phil Trans. B.</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/28playgroups/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/28playgroups/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Page, A. E., Emmott, E. H., Dyble, M., Smith, D., Chaudhary, N., Viguier, S., &amp;amp; Migliano, A. (2021) Children are important too: juvenile playgroups and maternal childcare in a foraging population, the Agta. Phil. Trans. R. Soc. B 376: 20200026.
Abstract
Non-maternal caregivers (allomothers) are hypothesised to lighten the mother’s workload, producing human’s specialised life history where multiple dependent offspring are produced over a relatively short time period. Here, using in-depth observational data on who for cares for 78 Agta children (aged 0-6 years, a foraging population in northern Philippines), we explore whether allomaternal childcare substitutes (and thus decreases) maternal childcare.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
