<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cooperative childrearing on Abigail E. Page</title>
    <link>https://abbeyepage.com/tags/cooperative-childrearing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cooperative childrearing on Abigail E. Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://abbeyepage.com/tags/cooperative-childrearing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Page, A. E., Emmott, E. H., and Myers, S. (Preprint) Testing the buffering hypothesis: breastfeeding problems, cessation and social support.</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/27bfprob/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/27bfprob/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Page, A. E., Emmott, E. H., and Myers, S. (2nd Revisions) Testing the buffering hypothesis: breastfeeding problems, cessation and social support. OSF Pre-print: https://osf.io/byf5g/.
Abstract
Objectives: Physical breastfeeding problems can lead women to terminate breastfeeding earlier than planned. In high-income countries, breastfeeding problems have been attributed to the cultural and individual “inexperience” of breastfeeding, ultimately leading to lower breastfeeding rates. Yet, cross-cultural evidence suggests breastfeeding problems still occur in contexts where breastfeeding is common, prolonged and seen publicly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Page, A. E. et al.  (2019) Testing adaptive hypotheses of alloparenting in Agta foragers. Nature Human Behaviour</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/10testhypo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/10testhypo/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Page, A. E., Thomas, M., Viguier, S., Dyble, M., Smith, D., Chaudhary, N., Salali, G., Thompson, J., Mace, R., and Migliano, A. B. (2019) Testing adaptive hypotheses of alloparenting in Agta foragers Nature Human Behaviour, 3: 1154–1163. doi.org/10.1038/s41562-019-0679-2.
Abstract
Human children are frequently cared for by non-parental caregivers (alloparents), yet few studies have conducted systematic alternative hypothesis tests of why alloparents help. Here we explore whether predictions from kin selection, reciprocity, learning-to-mother and costly signalling hypotheses explain non-parental childcare among Agta hunter-gatherers from the Philippines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emily, E. and Page, A. E. (2019) Alloparenting. Encyclopedia of Evolutionary Psychological Science </title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/11alloparent/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/11alloparent/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Emily, E. and Page, A. E. (2019) Alloparenting. In: Shackelford T., Weekes-Shackelford V. (eds) Encyclopedia of Evolutionary Psychological Science. Springer, Cham.
Abstract
Who helped you develop into the person you are today? Most of us may think about a parent or parents, but many of us would also recognize the important role of other people. Perhaps it’s a teacher, a grandparent, or a neighborhood friend. The fact that we are supported by many people in our childhood is, in fact, very unusual: In nonhuman mammals, support – or investments – for juveniles are typically and solely provided by the biological mother.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Childcare, parental investment, demography and diversity</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/projects/childcare/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/projects/childcare/</guid>
      <description>Status: Ongoing
Collaborators: Anushé Hassan (LSHTM), Sylvain Viguier (Graphcore, London), Mark Dyble (UCL), Daniel Smith (Bristol), Andrea Migliano (Zürich), Emily Emmott (UCL), Nikhil Chaudhary (Cambridge), Sarah Myers (UCL &amp;amp; MPI), Susie Lee (MPI), Rebecca Sear (LSHTM)
Funding: Medical Research Council
​
Non-maternal carers (allomothers) are hypothesized to lighten the mother’s workload, allowing for the specialized human life history including relatively short interbirth intervals and multiple dependent offspring. To date, evolutionary anthropology’s approach to understanding allomothering has largely (but not exclusively) investigated the ultimate explanations of allomothering (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infant feeding ideology, expectation and reality</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/projects/bfapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/projects/bfapp/</guid>
      <description>Status: Ongoing
Co-PIs: Emily Emmott (UCL) &amp;amp; Sarah Myers (UCL &amp;amp; MPI). Collaborators: Rebecca Sear (LSHTM) &amp;amp; Sylvain Viguier (Graphcore, London)
Funding: British Academy and Leverhulme Trust
​
BACKGROUND
Since the early 1990’s, breastfeeding has been on the global public health agenda, yet breastfeeding rates remain low. The UK performs particularly poorly; while 73% of women initiate, only 47.3% are still breastfeeding at 6-8 weeks. Despite this, many women report a desire to breastfeed for longer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social support, maternal experience and infant feeding</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/projects/bfsupport/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/projects/bfsupport/</guid>
      <description>Status: Wrapping up
Co-PIs: Emily Emmott (UCL) &amp;amp; Sarah Myers (UCL &amp;amp; MPI)
Funding: European Human Behaviour and Evolution Society
While the public health literature demonstrates a positive association between social support and breastfeeding, research has generally focused on informational and emotional support, overlooking practical help. Research also overlook wider sources of support, such as grandparents. Informed by evolutionary theory, we investigate how different types of support from different allomothers are associated with breastfeeding duration and maternal experience of infant feeding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cooperative childrearing, health and livelihood change in the Agta hunter-gatherers</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/projects/resilience/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/projects/resilience/</guid>
      <description>Status: Completed
PhD in Biologcal Anthropology at UCL
Collaborators: Sylvain Viguier (Graphcore, London), Mark Dyble (UCL), Daniel Smith (Bristol), Andrea Migliano (Zürich), Lucio Vinicius (Zürich), Ruth Mace (UCL), Deniz Salali (UCL), Nikhil Chaudhary (Cambridge), Mark Thomas (UCL)
Funding: The Leverhulme Trust
​
My PhD was part of the Hunter-gatherers Resilience Project at UCL which studied hunter-gatherers in Congo (Mbendjele), Malaysia(Batek), Thailand (Maniq) and the Philippines (Agta), using behavioural ecology, life history theory, theories of cooperation, cultural transmission and genetics to explore how variation in life history traits, kin selection, mate systems, cooperative behaviour, differentially contribute to hunter-gatherer resilience in the past, present and future.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
