<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Infant feeding on Abigail E. Page</title>
    <link>https://abbeyepage.com/tags/infant-feeding/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Infant feeding on Abigail E. Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://abbeyepage.com/tags/infant-feeding/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Page, A. E. et al. (2021) Children are important too. Phil Trans. B.</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/1playgroups/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/1playgroups/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Page, A. E., Emmott, E. H., Dyble, M., Smith, D., Chaudhary, N., Viguier, S., &amp;amp; Migliano, A. (2021) Children are important too: juvenile playgroups and maternal childcare in a foraging population, the Agta. Phil. Trans. R. Soc. B 376: 20200026.
Abstract
Non-maternal caregivers (allomothers) are hypothesised to lighten the mother’s workload, producing human’s specialised life history where multiple dependent offspring are produced over a relatively short time period. Here, using in-depth observational data on who for cares for 78 Agta children (aged 0-6 years, a foraging population in northern Philippines), we explore whether allomaternal childcare substitutes (and thus decreases) maternal childcare.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Page, A. E. et al. (2021) Children are important too. Phil Trans. B.</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/28playgroups/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/28playgroups/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Page, A. E., Emmott, E. H., Dyble, M., Smith, D., Chaudhary, N., Viguier, S., &amp;amp; Migliano, A. (2021) Children are important too: juvenile playgroups and maternal childcare in a foraging population, the Agta. Phil. Trans. R. Soc. B 376: 20200026.
Abstract
Non-maternal caregivers (allomothers) are hypothesised to lighten the mother’s workload, producing human’s specialised life history where multiple dependent offspring are produced over a relatively short time period. Here, using in-depth observational data on who for cares for 78 Agta children (aged 0-6 years, a foraging population in northern Philippines), we explore whether allomaternal childcare substitutes (and thus decreases) maternal childcare.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Page, A. E., Emmott, E. H., and Myers, S. Testing the buffering hypothesis: breastfeeding problems, cessation and social support.</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/27bfprob/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/27bfprob/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Page, A. E., Emmott, E. H., and Myers, S. (2nd Revisions) Testing the buffering hypothesis: breastfeeding problems, cessation and social support. OSF Pre-print: https://osf.io/byf5g/.
Abstract
Objectives: Physical breastfeeding problems can lead women to terminate breastfeeding earlier than planned. In high-income countries, breastfeeding problems have been attributed to the cultural and individual “inexperience” of breastfeeding, ultimately leading to lower breastfeeding rates. Yet, cross-cultural evidence suggests breastfeeding problems still occur in contexts where breastfeeding is common, prolonged and seen publicly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emmott, E. H, Page, A. E. &amp; Myers, S. (2020) Typologies response to comments. Social Science and Medicine</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/8typoreply/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/8typoreply/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Emmott, E. H, Page, A. E. &amp;amp; Myers, S. (2020) Typologies of postnatal support and breastfeeding at two months in the UK: Response to comments by Harpur and Haddon. Social Science and Medicine, 252:112944
Abstract
We welcome the comments by Harpur and Haddon (2020) on our paper on the typologies of social support and its associations with breastfeeding at two months in a UK sample. We share their concerns around the underacknowledged costs of breastfeeding, and the need for a truly family-centred approach to breastfeeding support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emmott, E. H, Page, A. E. &amp; Myers, S. (2020) Typologies of postnatal support and breastfeeding at two months in the UK. Social Science and Medicine</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/9typo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/9typo/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Emmott, E. H, Page, A. E. &amp;amp; Myers, S. (2020) Typologies of postnatal support and breastfeeding at two months in the UK. Social Science and Medicine, 246: 112791. doi.org/10.1016/j.socscimed.2020.112791.
Abstract
There is extensive evidence to suggest that social support improves breastfeeding outcomes. Building on this evidence-base, public health services and interventions aiming to improve breastfeeding rates have primarily targeted informational and emotional support to mothers, reflecting an individual behaviour-change approach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infant feeding ideology, expectation and reality</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/projects/bfapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/projects/bfapp/</guid>
      <description>Status: Ongoing
Co-PIs: Emily Emmott (UCL) &amp;amp; Sarah Myers (UCL &amp;amp; MPI). Collaborators: Rebecca Sear (LSHTM) &amp;amp; Sylvain Viguier (Graphcore, London)
Funding: British Academy and Leverhulme Trust
​
BACKGROUND
Since the early 1990’s, breastfeeding has been on the global public health agenda, yet breastfeeding rates remain low. The UK performs particularly poorly; while 73% of women initiate, only 47.3% are still breastfeeding at 6-8 weeks. Despite this, many women report a desire to breastfeed for longer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social support, maternal experience and infant feeding</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/projects/bfsupport/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/projects/bfsupport/</guid>
      <description>Status: Wrapping up
Co-PIs: Emily Emmott (UCL) &amp;amp; Sarah Myers (UCL &amp;amp; MPI)
Funding: European Human Behaviour and Evolution Society
While the public health literature demonstrates a positive association between social support and breastfeeding, research has generally focused on informational and emotional support, overlooking practical help. Research also overlook wider sources of support, such as grandparents. Informed by evolutionary theory, we investigate how different types of support from different allomothers are associated with breastfeeding duration and maternal experience of infant feeding.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
