<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Parental investment on Abigail E. Page</title>
    <link>https://abbeyepage.com/tags/parental-investment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Parental investment on Abigail E. Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 12:41:05 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://abbeyepage.com/tags/parental-investment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Page, A. E. et al. (2019) Why so many Agta boys. Evolutionary Human Sciences</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/12boys/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/12boys/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Page, A. E^., Myers, S^., Dyble, M. and Migliano, A. B. (2019) Why so many Agta boys? Explaining extreme sex ratios in Philippine forgers. Evolutionary Human Sciences, 1: e5. ^joint first authors.
Abstract
Male-biased sex ratios have been observed in multiple small-scale societies. Although intentional and systematic female-biased mortality has been posited as an explanation, there is often a lack of ethnographic evidence of systematic female neglect and/or infanticide. The Agta, a foraging population from the Philippines, have a skewed sex ratio of 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Childcare, parental investment, demography and diversity</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/projects/childcare/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/projects/childcare/</guid>
      <description>Status: Ongoing
Collaborators: Anushé Hassan (LSHTM), Sylvain Viguier (Graphcore, London), Mark Dyble (UCL), Daniel Smith (Bristol), Andrea Migliano (Zürich), Emily Emmott (UCL), Nikhil Chaudhary (Cambridge), Sarah Myers (UCL &amp;amp; MPI), Susie Lee (MPI), Rebecca Sear (LSHTM)
Funding: Medical Research Council
​
Non-maternal carers (allomothers) are hypothesized to lighten the mother’s workload, allowing for the specialized human life history including relatively short interbirth intervals and multiple dependent offspring. To date, evolutionary anthropology’s approach to understanding allomothering has largely (but not exclusively) investigated the ultimate explanations of allomothering (i.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
