<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alloparenting on Abigail E. Page</title>
    <link>https://abbeyepage.github.io/tags/alloparenting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Alloparenting on Abigail E. Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://abbeyepage.github.io/tags/alloparenting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Page, A. E. et al.  (2019) Testing adaptive hypotheses of alloparenting in Agta foragers. Nature Human Behaviour</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.github.io/publications/10testhypo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.github.io/publications/10testhypo/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Page, A. E., Thomas, M., Viguier, S., Dyble, M., Smith, D., Chaudhary, N., Salali, G., Thompson, J., Mace, R., and Migliano, A. B. (2019) Testing adaptive hypotheses of alloparenting in Agta foragers Nature Human Behaviour, 3: 1154–1163. doi.org/10.1038/s41562-019-0679-2.
Abstract
Human children are frequently cared for by non-parental caregivers (alloparents), yet few studies have conducted systematic alternative hypothesis tests of why alloparents help. Here we explore whether predictions from kin selection, reciprocity, learning-to-mother and costly signalling hypotheses explain non-parental childcare among Agta hunter-gatherers from the Philippines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emily, E. and Page, A. E. (2019) Alloparenting. Encyclopedia of Evolutionary Psychological Science </title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.github.io/publications/11alloparent/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.github.io/publications/11alloparent/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Emily, E. and Page, A. E. (2019) Alloparenting. In: Shackelford T., Weekes-Shackelford V. (eds) Encyclopedia of Evolutionary Psychological Science. Springer, Cham.
Abstract
Who helped you develop into the person you are today? Most of us may think about a parent or parents, but many of us would also recognize the important role of other people. Perhaps it’s a teacher, a grandparent, or a neighborhood friend. The fact that we are supported by many people in our childhood is, in fact, very unusual: In nonhuman mammals, support – or investments – for juveniles are typically and solely provided by the biological mother.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
