<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Demography on Abigail E. Page</title>
    <link>https://abbeyepage.github.io/tags/demography/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Demography on Abigail E. Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 12:41:05 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://abbeyepage.github.io/tags/demography/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Page, A. E. and French, J. C. (2020) Reconstructing prehistoric demography. Evolutionary Anthropology</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.github.io/publications/5hgdemo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.github.io/publications/5hgdemo/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Page, A. E. and French, J. C. (2020) Reconstructing prehistoric demography: What role for extant hunter-gatherers? Evolutionary Anthropology, 29(6): 332-345. doi.org/10.1002/evan.21869
Abstract
Demography is central to biological, behavioral, and cultural evolution. Knowledge of the demography of prehistoric populations of both Homo sapiens and earlier members of the genus Homo is, therefore, key to the study of human evolution. Unfortunately, demographic processes (fertility, mortality, migration) leave little mark on the archeological and paleoanthropological records.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Childcare, parental investment, demography and diversity</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.github.io/projects/childcare/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.github.io/projects/childcare/</guid>
      <description>Status: Ongoing
Collaborators: Anushé Hassan (LSHTM), Sylvain Viguier (Graphcore, London), Mark Dyble (UCL), Daniel Smith (Bristol), Andrea Migliano (Zürich), Emily Emmott (UCL), Nikhil Chaudhary (Cambridge), Sarah Myers (UCL &amp;amp; MPI), Susie Lee (MPI), Rebecca Sear (LSHTM)
Funding: Medical Research Council
​
Non-maternal carers (allomothers) are hypothesized to lighten the mother’s workload, allowing for the specialized human life history including relatively short interbirth intervals and multiple dependent offspring. To date, evolutionary anthropology’s approach to understanding allomothering has largely (but not exclusively) investigated the ultimate explanations of allomothering (i.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
