<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wireless sensing networks on Abigail E. Page</title>
    <link>https://abbeyepage.github.io/tags/wireless-sensing-networks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wireless sensing networks on Abigail E. Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://abbeyepage.github.io/tags/wireless-sensing-networks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Migliano, A. B. et al. (2020) Hunter-gatherers multilevel sociality accelerates the evolution of cumulative culture. Science Advances</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.github.io/publications/7hgcumcul/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.github.io/publications/7hgcumcul/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Migliano, A. B., Battiston, F., Viguier, S., Page, A. E., Dyble, M., Schlaepfer, R., Smith, D., Astete, L., Ngales, M., Gomez-Gardenes, Latora, V., Vinicius, L (2020) Hunter-gatherers multilevel sociality accelerates the evolution of cumulative culture. Science Advances, 6(9): eaax5913
Abstract
Although multilevel sociality is a universal feature of human social organization, its functional relevance remains unclear. Here, we investigated the effect of multilevel sociality on cumulative cultural evolution by using wireless sensing technology to map inter- and intraband social networks among Agta hunter-gatherers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migliano, A.B., et al. (2017) Characterization of hunter-gatherer networks and implications for cumulative culture. Nature Human Behaviour</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.github.io/publications/19cumcult/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.github.io/publications/19cumcult/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Migliano, A.B., Page, A.E., Gómez-Gardeñes, J., Salali, G.D., Viguier, S., Dyble, M., Thompson, J., Chaudhary, N., Smith, D., Strods, J., Mace, R., Thomas, M.G., Latora, V., Vinicius, L., (2017) Characterization of hunter-gatherer networks and implications for cumulative culture. Nature Human Behaviour, 1: 1–6.
Abstract
Social networks in modern societies are highly structured, usually involving frequent contact with a small number of unrelated ‘friends’. However, contact network structures in traditional small-scale societies, especially hunter-gatherers, are poorly characterized.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
