<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mortality on Abigail E. Page</title>
    <link>https://abbeyepage.com/tags/mortality/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mortality on Abigail E. Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://abbeyepage.com/tags/mortality/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Page, A. E. et al. (2019) Why so many Agta boys. Evolutionary Human Sciences</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/12boys/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/12boys/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Page, A. E^., Myers, S^., Dyble, M. and Migliano, A. B. (2019) Why so many Agta boys? Explaining extreme sex ratios in Philippine forgers. Evolutionary Human Sciences, 1: e5. ^joint first authors.
Abstract
Male-biased sex ratios have been observed in multiple small-scale societies. Although intentional and systematic female-biased mortality has been posited as an explanation, there is often a lack of ethnographic evidence of systematic female neglect and/or infanticide. The Agta, a foraging population from the Philippines, have a skewed sex ratio of 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Page, A. E., et al. (2016) Reproductive trade-offs in extant hunter-gatherers suggest adaptive mechanism for the Neolithic expansion. PNAS</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/21tradeoff/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/21tradeoff/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Page, A. E., Viguier, S., Dyble, M., Smith, D., Chaudhary, N., Salali, G., Thompson, J., Vinicius, L., Mace, R., and Migliano, A. B. (2016) Reproductive trade-offs in extant hunter-gatherers suggest adaptive mechanism for the Neolithic expansion. PNAS, 113 (17): 4694-4699.
Abstract
The Neolithic demographic transition remains a paradox, because it is associated with both higher rates of population growth and increased morbidity and mortality rates. Here we reconcile the conflicting evidence by proposing that the spread of agriculture involved a life history quality–quantity trade-off whereby mothers traded offspring survival for increased fertility, achieving greater reproductive success despite deteriorating health.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
