<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>BaYaka on Abigail E. Page</title>
    <link>https://abbeyepage.com/tags/bayaka/</link>
    <description>Recent content in BaYaka on Abigail E. Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://abbeyepage.com/tags/bayaka/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Diekmann, Y., et al. (2017) Accurate age estimation in small-scale societies. PNAS</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/18age/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/18age/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Diekmann, Y., Smith, D., Gerbault, P., Dyble, M., Page, A.E., Chaudhary, N., Migliano, A.B., Thomas, M.G. (2017) Accurate age estimation in small-scale societies. PNAS, 114 (31): 8205-8210.
Abstract
Precise estimation of age is essential in evolutionary anthropology, especially to infer population age structures and understand the evolution of human life history diversity. However, in small-scale societies, such as hunter-gatherer populations, time is often not referred to in calendar years, and accurate age estimation remains a challenge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Page, A. E., et al. (2017) Hunter-Gatherer Social Networks and Reproductive Success. Scientific Reports</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/17hgnetwork/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/17hgnetwork/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Page, A. E., Chaudhary, N., Viguier, S., Dyble, M., Smith, D., Salali, G., Thompson, J., Mace, R., &amp;amp;Migliano, A.B. (2017) Hunter-Gatherer Social Networks and Reproductive Success. Scientific Reports, 7: 1153.
Abstract
Individuals’ centrality in their social network (who they and their social ties are connected to) has been associated with fertility, longevity, disease and information transmission in a range of taxa. Here, we present the first exploration in humans of the relationship between reproductive success and different measures of network centrality of 39 Agta and 38 BaYaka mothers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migliano, A.B., et al. (2017) Characterization of hunter-gatherer networks and implications for cumulative culture. Nature Human Behaviour</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/19cumcult/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/19cumcult/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Migliano, A.B., Page, A.E., Gómez-Gardeñes, J., Salali, G.D., Viguier, S., Dyble, M., Thompson, J., Chaudhary, N., Smith, D., Strods, J., Mace, R., Thomas, M.G., Latora, V., Vinicius, L., (2017) Characterization of hunter-gatherer networks and implications for cumulative culture. Nature Human Behaviour, 1: 1–6.
Abstract
Social networks in modern societies are highly structured, usually involving frequent contact with a small number of unrelated ‘friends’. However, contact network structures in traditional small-scale societies, especially hunter-gatherers, are poorly characterized.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Salali, G.D, et al. (2016) Knowledge-sharing networks in hunter-gatherers and the evolution of cumulative culture. Current Biology</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/22knowshare/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/22knowshare/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Salali, G.D., Chaudhary, N., Thompson, J., Grace, O.M., Burgt, X.M. van der, Dyble, M., Page, A.E., Smith, D., Lewis, J., Mace, R., Vinicius, L., Migliano, A.B. (2016) Knowledge-sharing networks in hunter-gatherers and the evolution of cumulative culture. Current Biology, 26 (18): 2516-2521.
Abstract
Humans possess the unique ability for cumulative culture. It has been argued that hunter-gatherer’s complex social structure has facilitated the evolution of cumulative culture by allowing information exchange among large pools of individuals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dyble, M., et al. (2016) Networks of food sharing reveal the functional significance of multilevel sociality in two hunter-gatherer groups. Current Biology</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/20multilevel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/20multilevel/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Dyble, M., Thompson, J., Page, A.E., Chaudhary, N., Salali, G.D., Vinicius, L., Mace, R., Migliano, A.B. (2016) Networks of food sharing reveal the functional significance of multilevel sociality in two hunter-gatherer groups. Current Biology, 26 (15): 2017-2021.
Abstract
Like many other mammalian and primate societies, humans are said to live in multilevel social groups, with individuals situated in a series of hierarchically structured sub-groups. Although this multilevel social organization has been described among contemporary hunter-gatherers, questions remain as to the benefits that individuals derive from living in such groups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chaudhary, N. et al. (2016) Within-Group Competition for Cooperation among BaYaka Hunter-Gatherers. Scientific Reports</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/24compcoop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/24compcoop/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Chaudhary, N., Salali, G., Thompson, J. Page, A. E., Smith, D., Dyble, M., Mace, R., and Migliano, A. (2016) Within-Group Competition for Cooperation among BaYaka Hunter-Gatherers. Scientific Reports, 6: 29120.
Abstract
Humans regularly cooperate with non-kin, which has been theorized to require reciprocity between repeatedly interacting and trusting individuals. However, the role of repeated interactions has not previously been demonstrated in explaining real-world patterns of hunter–gatherer cooperation. Here we explore cooperation among the Agta, a population of Filipino hunter–gatherers, using data from both actual resource transfers and two experimental games across multiple camps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chaudhary, N. et al. (2016) Polygyny without wealth: Popularity in gift games predicts polygyny in BaYaka Pygmies. Royal Society Open Science</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/26polygyny/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/26polygyny/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Chaudhary, N., Salali, G., Thompson, J., Dyble, M., Page, A. E., Smith, D., Mace, R., and Migliano, A. (2015) Polygyny without wealth: Popularity in gift games predicts polygyny in BaYaka Pygmies. Royal Society Open Science, 2: 150054.
Abstract
The occurrence of polygynous marriage in hunter–gatherer societies, which do not accumulate wealth, remains largely unexplored since resource availability is dependent on male hunting capacity and limited by the lack of storage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dyble, M. et al. (2016) Sex equality can explain the unique social structure of hunter-gatherer bands. Science</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/25sexequality/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/25sexequality/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Dyble, M., Salali, G., Chaudhary, N., Page, A. E, Thompson, J., Smith, D., Vinicius, L., Mace, R., and Migliano, A. (2015) Sex equality can explain the unique social structure of hunter-gatherer bands. Science, 348(6236): 796-8.
Abstract
The social organization of mobile hunter-gatherers has several derived features, including low within-camp relatedness and fluid meta-groups. Although these features have been proposed to have provided the selective context for the evolution of human hypercooperation and cumulative culture, how such a distinctive social system may have emerged remains unclear.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
