<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reciprocity on Abigail E. Page</title>
    <link>https://abbeyepage.com/tags/reciprocity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reciprocity on Abigail E. Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://abbeyepage.com/tags/reciprocity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Smith D., et al. (2018) A Friend in Need is a Friend Indeed. Evolution and Human Behaviour.</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/15friend/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/15friend/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Smith D., Major, K., Dyble, M., Page, A.E., Migliano, A.B., Thompson, J., Chaudhary, N., Salali, G.D., Vinicius, L. and Mace, R. (2018) A Friend in Need is a Friend Indeed: Need-based sharing, rather than cooperative assortment, predicts experimental resource transfers among Agta hunter-gatherers. Evolution and Human Behaviour, doi.org/10.1016/j.evolhumbehav.2018.08.004.
Abstract
Despite much theorizing, the evolutionary reasons why humans cooperate extensively with unrelated individuals are still largely unknown. While reciprocity explains many instances of non-kin cooperation, much remains to be understood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smith, D. et al. (2016) Camp Stability Predicts Patterns of Hunter-Gatherer Cooperation. Royal Society Open Science</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/23stablity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/23stablity/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Smith, D., Dyble, M., Thompson, J., Major, K., Page, A. E., Chaudhary, N., Salali, G., Vinicius, L., Migliano, A. B. and Mace, R. (2016) Camp Stability Predicts Patterns of Hunter-Gatherer Cooperation. Royal Society Open Science, 3: 160131.
Abstract
Humans regularly cooperate with non-kin, which has been theorized to require reciprocity between repeatedly interacting and trusting individuals. However, the role of repeated interactions has not previously been demonstrated in explaining real-world patterns of hunter–gatherer cooperation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
