<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cooperation on Abigail E. Page</title>
    <link>https://abbeyepage.github.io/tags/cooperation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cooperation on Abigail E. Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://abbeyepage.github.io/tags/cooperation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Smith D., et al. (2018) A Friend in Need is a Friend Indeed. Evolution and Human Behaviour.</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.github.io/publications/15friend/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.github.io/publications/15friend/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Smith D., Major, K., Dyble, M., Page, A.E., Migliano, A.B., Thompson, J., Chaudhary, N., Salali, G.D., Vinicius, L. and Mace, R. (2018) A Friend in Need is a Friend Indeed: Need-based sharing, rather than cooperative assortment, predicts experimental resource transfers among Agta hunter-gatherers. Evolution and Human Behaviour, doi.org/10.1016/j.evolhumbehav.2018.08.004.
Abstract
Despite much theorizing, the evolutionary reasons why humans cooperate extensively with unrelated individuals are still largely unknown. While reciprocity explains many instances of non-kin cooperation, much remains to be understood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smith, D., et al. (2017) Cooperation and the evolution of hunter-gatherer storytelling. Nature Communications.</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.github.io/publications/16story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.github.io/publications/16story/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Smith, D., Schlaepfer, P., Major, K., Dyble, M., Page, A.E., Thompson, J., Chaudhary, N., Salali, G.D., Mace, R., Vinicius, L., and Migliano, A.B. (2017) Cooperation and the evolution of hunter-gatherer storytelling. Nature Communications, 8 (1853): doi:10.1038/s41467-017-02036-8.
Abstract
Storytelling is a human universal. From gathering around the camp-fire telling tales of ancestors to watching the latest television box-set, humans are inveterate producers and consumers of stories. Despite its ubiquity, little attention has been given to understanding the function and evolution of storytelling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Page, A. E., et al. (2017) Hunter-Gatherer Social Networks and Reproductive Success. Scientific Reports</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.github.io/publications/17hgnetwork/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.github.io/publications/17hgnetwork/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Page, A. E., Chaudhary, N., Viguier, S., Dyble, M., Smith, D., Salali, G., Thompson, J., Mace, R., &amp;amp;Migliano, A.B. (2017) Hunter-Gatherer Social Networks and Reproductive Success. Scientific Reports, 7: 1153.
Abstract
Individuals’ centrality in their social network (who they and their social ties are connected to) has been associated with fertility, longevity, disease and information transmission in a range of taxa. Here, we present the first exploration in humans of the relationship between reproductive success and different measures of network centrality of 39 Agta and 38 BaYaka mothers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chaudhary, N. et al. (2016) Within-Group Competition for Cooperation among BaYaka Hunter-Gatherers. Scientific Reports</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.github.io/publications/24compcoop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.github.io/publications/24compcoop/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Chaudhary, N., Salali, G., Thompson, J. Page, A. E., Smith, D., Dyble, M., Mace, R., and Migliano, A. (2016) Within-Group Competition for Cooperation among BaYaka Hunter-Gatherers. Scientific Reports, 6: 29120.
Abstract
Humans regularly cooperate with non-kin, which has been theorized to require reciprocity between repeatedly interacting and trusting individuals. However, the role of repeated interactions has not previously been demonstrated in explaining real-world patterns of hunter–gatherer cooperation. Here we explore cooperation among the Agta, a population of Filipino hunter–gatherers, using data from both actual resource transfers and two experimental games across multiple camps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smith, D. et al. (2016) Camp Stability Predicts Patterns of Hunter-Gatherer Cooperation. Royal Society Open Science</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.github.io/publications/23stablity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.github.io/publications/23stablity/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Smith, D., Dyble, M., Thompson, J., Major, K., Page, A. E., Chaudhary, N., Salali, G., Vinicius, L., Migliano, A. B. and Mace, R. (2016) Camp Stability Predicts Patterns of Hunter-Gatherer Cooperation. Royal Society Open Science, 3: 160131.
Abstract
Humans regularly cooperate with non-kin, which has been theorized to require reciprocity between repeatedly interacting and trusting individuals. However, the role of repeated interactions has not previously been demonstrated in explaining real-world patterns of hunter–gatherer cooperation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
