<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Multidisciplinary on Abigail E. Page</title>
    <link>https://abbeyepage.com/tags/multidisciplinary/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Multidisciplinary on Abigail E. Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://abbeyepage.com/tags/multidisciplinary/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Emmott, E. H., Myers, S. and Page, A. E. (2021) Who cares for women with children? Phil Trans. B.</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/2editoral/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/2editoral/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Emmott, E. H., Myers, S. and Page, A. E. (2021) Who cares for women with children? Crossing the bridge between disciplines. Phil Trans. B&amp;hellip;..
Abstract
It has long been acknowledged that women with children require social support to promote their health and wellbeing, as well as that of their children. However, the dominant conceptualizations of support have been heavily influenced by Western family norms. The consequence, at best, has been to stifle our understanding of the nature and consequences of support for mothers and children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multidisciplinary Perspectives on Social Support and Maternal Child Health: Guest edited issue of Phil. Trans. B.</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/3specialissue/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/3specialissue/</guid>
      <description>It is widely acknowledged that women with children require high levels of social support to promote their, and their children’s, health and wellbeing. However, studies on social support often take overly narrow Western perspectives, leading to biased understandings of support and its impact on maternal-child health. We know social support is complex, coming in different forms and from different sources, influenced by environmental context. In this multidisciplinary special issue, we explore social support from different perspectives: While Western norms assume that childcare comes under the responsibility of mothers, in reality, childrearing is widely shared and supported in different ways across societies.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
