<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Neolithic demographic transition on Abigail E. Page</title>
    <link>https://abbeyepage.com/tags/neolithic-demographic-transition/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Neolithic demographic transition on Abigail E. Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 12:41:05 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://abbeyepage.com/tags/neolithic-demographic-transition/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fertility and subsistence - a cross-cultural analysis</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/projects/fert/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/projects/fert/</guid>
      <description>Status: Ongoing
Co-PI: Rebecca Sear (LSHTM).
Collaborators: Colette Berbesque, Jeremy Koster, Monique Borgerhoff Mulder, Heidi Colleran, Karen Kramer, Siohban Mattison, Brooke Scelza, Mary Shenk, Jonathan Stieglitz, John Ziker, Cody Ross, Katie Starkweather, Luis Pacheco-Cobos, Ryan Schacht, Sheina Lew-Levy, Adam Boyette, Shane Macfarlan, Christina Moya, Jennifer French
​
BACKGROUND
There has long been academic interest in the relationship between fertility and mode of subsistence, spanning anthropology, demography and archaeology. From a prehistoric perspective, archaeologists have pointed to significant population expansions, often referred to as the Neolithic Demographic Transition, due to significant increases in fertility associated, and arguably caused by, the onset of agriculture 12,000-6,000 BP (Diamond, 2002; Diamond and Bellwood, 2003; Bocquet-Appel, 2008; Guerrero, Naji and Bocquet‐Appel, 2008).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cooperative childrearing, health and livelihood change in the Agta hunter-gatherers</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/projects/resilience/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/projects/resilience/</guid>
      <description>Status: Completed
PhD in Biologcal Anthropology at UCL
Collaborators: Sylvain Viguier (Graphcore, London), Mark Dyble (UCL), Daniel Smith (Bristol), Andrea Migliano (Zürich), Lucio Vinicius (Zürich), Ruth Mace (UCL), Deniz Salali (UCL), Nikhil Chaudhary (Cambridge), Mark Thomas (UCL)
Funding: The Leverhulme Trust
​
My PhD was part of the Hunter-gatherers Resilience Project at UCL which studied hunter-gatherers in Congo (Mbendjele), Malaysia(Batek), Thailand (Maniq) and the Philippines (Agta), using behavioural ecology, life history theory, theories of cooperation, cultural transmission and genetics to explore how variation in life history traits, kin selection, mate systems, cooperative behaviour, differentially contribute to hunter-gatherer resilience in the past, present and future.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
