<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fertility on Abigail E. Page</title>
    <link>https://abbeyepage.com/tags/fertility/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fertility on Abigail E. Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 12:41:05 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://abbeyepage.com/tags/fertility/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Page, A. E. and French, J. C. (2020) Reconstructing prehistoric demography. Evolutionary Anthropology</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/5hgdemo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/5hgdemo/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Page, A. E. and French, J. C. (2020) Reconstructing prehistoric demography: What role for extant hunter-gatherers? Evolutionary Anthropology, 29(6): 332-345. doi.org/10.1002/evan.21869
Abstract
Demography is central to biological, behavioral, and cultural evolution. Knowledge of the demography of prehistoric populations of both Homo sapiens and earlier members of the genus Homo is, therefore, key to the study of human evolution. Unfortunately, demographic processes (fertility, mortality, migration) leave little mark on the archeological and paleoanthropological records.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Page, A. E., et al. (2016) Reproductive trade-offs in extant hunter-gatherers suggest adaptive mechanism for the Neolithic expansion. PNAS</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/21tradeoff/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/21tradeoff/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Page, A. E., Viguier, S., Dyble, M., Smith, D., Chaudhary, N., Salali, G., Thompson, J., Vinicius, L., Mace, R., and Migliano, A. B. (2016) Reproductive trade-offs in extant hunter-gatherers suggest adaptive mechanism for the Neolithic expansion. PNAS, 113 (17): 4694-4699.
Abstract
The Neolithic demographic transition remains a paradox, because it is associated with both higher rates of population growth and increased morbidity and mortality rates. Here we reconcile the conflicting evidence by proposing that the spread of agriculture involved a life history quality–quantity trade-off whereby mothers traded offspring survival for increased fertility, achieving greater reproductive success despite deteriorating health.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fertility and subsistence - a cross-cultural analysis</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/projects/fert/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/projects/fert/</guid>
      <description>Status: Ongoing
Co-PI: Rebecca Sear (LSHTM).
Collaborators: Colette Berbesque, Jeremy Koster, Monique Borgerhoff Mulder, Heidi Colleran, Karen Kramer, Siohban Mattison, Brooke Scelza, Mary Shenk, Jonathan Stieglitz, John Ziker, Cody Ross, Katie Starkweather, Luis Pacheco-Cobos, Ryan Schacht, Sheina Lew-Levy, Adam Boyette, Shane Macfarlan, Christina Moya, Jennifer French
​
BACKGROUND
There has long been academic interest in the relationship between fertility and mode of subsistence, spanning anthropology, demography and archaeology. From a prehistoric perspective, archaeologists have pointed to significant population expansions, often referred to as the Neolithic Demographic Transition, due to significant increases in fertility associated, and arguably caused by, the onset of agriculture 12,000-6,000 BP (Diamond, 2002; Diamond and Bellwood, 2003; Bocquet-Appel, 2008; Guerrero, Naji and Bocquet‐Appel, 2008).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
