<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications on Abigail E. Page</title>
    <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publications on Abigail E. Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 16:47:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://abbeyepage.com/publications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Page, A. E. et al. (2021) Children are important too. Phil Trans. B.</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/1playgroups/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/1playgroups/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Page, A. E., Emmott, E. H., Dyble, M., Smith, D., Chaudhary, N., Viguier, S., &amp;amp; Migliano, A. (2021) Children are important too: juvenile playgroups and maternal childcare in a foraging population, the Agta. Phil. Trans. R. Soc. B 376: 20200026.
Abstract
Non-maternal caregivers (allomothers) are hypothesised to lighten the mother’s workload, producing human’s specialised life history where multiple dependent offspring are produced over a relatively short time period. Here, using in-depth observational data on who for cares for 78 Agta children (aged 0-6 years, a foraging population in northern Philippines), we explore whether allomaternal childcare substitutes (and thus decreases) maternal childcare.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emmott, E. H., Myers, S. and Page, A. E. (2021) Who cares for women with children? Phil Trans. B.</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/2editoral/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/2editoral/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Emmott, E. H., Myers, S. and Page, A. E. (2021) Who cares for women with children? Crossing the bridge between disciplines. Trans. R. Soc. B 376: 20200019
Abstract
It has long been acknowledged that women with children require social support to promote their health and wellbeing, as well as that of their children. However, the dominant conceptualizations of support have been heavily influenced by Western family norms. The consequence, at best, has been to stifle our understanding of the nature and consequences of support for mothers and children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multidisciplinary Perspectives on Social Support and Maternal Child Health: Guest edited issue of Phil. Trans. B.</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/3specialissue/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/3specialissue/</guid>
      <description>It is widely acknowledged that women with children require high levels of social support to promote their, and their children’s, health and wellbeing. However, studies on social support often take overly narrow Western perspectives, leading to biased understandings of support and its impact on maternal-child health. We know social support is complex, coming in different forms and from different sources, influenced by environmental context. In this multidisciplinary special issue, we explore social support from different perspectives: While Western norms assume that childcare comes under the responsibility of mothers, in reality, childrearing is widely shared and supported in different ways across societies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Myers, S., Page, A. E. and Emmott, E. H., (2021) The differential role of practical and emotional support in infant feeding experience in the UK? Phil Trans. B.</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/4infantfeeding/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/4infantfeeding/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Myers, S., Page, A. E. and Emmott, E. H., (2021) The differential role of practical and emotional support in infant feeding experience in the UK? Trans. R. Soc. B 376: 20200034
Abstract
Social support is a known determinant of breastfeeding behaviour and is generally considered beneficial. However, social support encompasses a myriad of different supportive acts, providing scope for diverse infant feeding outcomes. Given the vulnerability of postpartum mental health, this paper aims to explore both how support prolongs breastfeeding and which forms of support promote the positive experience of all infant feeding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Page, A. E., Emmott, E. H., and Myers, S. Testing the buffering hypothesis: breastfeeding problems, cessation and social support.</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/27bfprob/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/27bfprob/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Page, A. E., Emmott, E. H., and Myers, S. (2nd Revisions) Testing the buffering hypothesis: breastfeeding problems, cessation and social support. OSF Pre-print: https://osf.io/byf5g/.
Abstract
Objectives: Physical breastfeeding problems can lead women to terminate breastfeeding earlier than planned. In high-income countries, breastfeeding problems have been attributed to the cultural and individual “inexperience” of breastfeeding, ultimately leading to lower breastfeeding rates. Yet, cross-cultural evidence suggests breastfeeding problems still occur in contexts where breastfeeding is common, prolonged and seen publicly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Page, A. E. and French, J. C. (2020) Reconstructing prehistoric demography. Evolutionary Anthropology</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/5hgdemo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/5hgdemo/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Page, A. E. and French, J. C. (2020) Reconstructing prehistoric demography: What role for extant hunter-gatherers? Evolutionary Anthropology, 29(6): 332-345. doi.org/10.1002/evan.21869
Abstract
Demography is central to biological, behavioral, and cultural evolution. Knowledge of the demography of prehistoric populations of both Homo sapiens and earlier members of the genus Homo is, therefore, key to the study of human evolution. Unfortunately, demographic processes (fertility, mortality, migration) leave little mark on the archeological and paleoanthropological records.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brown, L. J. et al. (2020) Subjective Environmental Experiences and Women’s Breastfeeding Journeys. IERPH</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/6bfenviro/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/6bfenviro/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Brown, L. J., Myers, S., Page, A. E., and Emmott, E. (2020) Subjective Environmental Experiences and Women’s Breastfeeding Journeys: A Survival Analysis Using an Online Survey of UK Mothers. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health, 17(21), 7903: doi.org/10.3390/ijerph17217903.
Abstract
Local physical and social environmental factors are important drivers of human health and behaviour. Environmental perception has been linked with both reproduction and parenting, but links between subjective environmental experiences and breastfeeding remain unclear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emmott, E. H, Page, A. E. &amp; Myers, S. (2020) Typologies response to comments. Social Science and Medicine</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/8typoreply/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/8typoreply/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Emmott, E. H, Page, A. E. &amp;amp; Myers, S. (2020) Typologies of postnatal support and breastfeeding at two months in the UK: Response to comments by Harpur and Haddon. Social Science and Medicine, 252:112944
Abstract
We welcome the comments by Harpur and Haddon (2020) on our paper on the typologies of social support and its associations with breastfeeding at two months in a UK sample. We share their concerns around the underacknowledged costs of breastfeeding, and the need for a truly family-centred approach to breastfeeding support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migliano, A. B. et al. (2020) Hunter-gatherers multilevel sociality accelerates the evolution of cumulative culture. Science Advances</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/7hgcumcul/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/7hgcumcul/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Migliano, A. B., Battiston, F., Viguier, S., Page, A. E., Dyble, M., Schlaepfer, R., Smith, D., Astete, L., Ngales, M., Gomez-Gardenes, Latora, V., Vinicius, L (2020) Hunter-gatherers multilevel sociality accelerates the evolution of cumulative culture. Science Advances, 6(9): eaax5913
Abstract
Although multilevel sociality is a universal feature of human social organization, its functional relevance remains unclear. Here, we investigated the effect of multilevel sociality on cumulative cultural evolution by using wireless sensing technology to map inter- and intraband social networks among Agta hunter-gatherers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emmott, E. H, Page, A. E. &amp; Myers, S. (2020) Typologies of postnatal support and breastfeeding at two months in the UK. Social Science and Medicine</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/9typo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/9typo/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Emmott, E. H, Page, A. E. &amp;amp; Myers, S. (2020) Typologies of postnatal support and breastfeeding at two months in the UK. Social Science and Medicine, 246: 112791. doi.org/10.1016/j.socscimed.2020.112791.
Abstract
There is extensive evidence to suggest that social support improves breastfeeding outcomes. Building on this evidence-base, public health services and interventions aiming to improve breastfeeding rates have primarily targeted informational and emotional support to mothers, reflecting an individual behaviour-change approach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Page, A. E. et al.  (2019) Testing adaptive hypotheses of alloparenting in Agta foragers. Nature Human Behaviour</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/10testhypo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/10testhypo/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Page, A. E., Thomas, M., Viguier, S., Dyble, M., Smith, D., Chaudhary, N., Salali, G., Thompson, J., Mace, R., and Migliano, A. B. (2019) Testing adaptive hypotheses of alloparenting in Agta foragers Nature Human Behaviour, 3: 1154–1163. doi.org/10.1038/s41562-019-0679-2.
Abstract
Human children are frequently cared for by non-parental caregivers (alloparents), yet few studies have conducted systematic alternative hypothesis tests of why alloparents help. Here we explore whether predictions from kin selection, reciprocity, learning-to-mother and costly signalling hypotheses explain non-parental childcare among Agta hunter-gatherers from the Philippines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emily, E. and Page, A. E. (2019) Alloparenting. Encyclopedia of Evolutionary Psychological Science </title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/11alloparent/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/11alloparent/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Emily, E. and Page, A. E. (2019) Alloparenting. In: Shackelford T., Weekes-Shackelford V. (eds) Encyclopedia of Evolutionary Psychological Science. Springer, Cham.
Abstract
Who helped you develop into the person you are today? Most of us may think about a parent or parents, but many of us would also recognize the important role of other people. Perhaps it’s a teacher, a grandparent, or a neighborhood friend. The fact that we are supported by many people in our childhood is, in fact, very unusual: In nonhuman mammals, support – or investments – for juveniles are typically and solely provided by the biological mother.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dyble, M. et al.  (2019) Engagement in agricultural work is associated with reduced leisure time among Agta hunter-gatherers. Nature Human Behaviour.</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/13lesiure/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/13lesiure/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Dyble, M., Thorley, J., Page, A. E., Smith, D., and Migliano, A. B. (2019) Engagement in agricultural work is associated with reduced leisure time among Agta hunter-gatherers. Nature Human Behaviour. doi.org/10.1038/s41562-019-0614-6.
Abstract
A long-standing hypothesis suggests that the transition from hunting and gathering to agriculture results in people working harder, spending more time engaged in subsistence activities and having less leisure time. However, tests of this hypothesis are obscured by comparing between populations that vary in ecology and social organization, as well as subsistence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Page, A. E. et al. (2019) Why so many Agta boys. Evolutionary Human Sciences</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/12boys/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/12boys/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Page, A. E^., Myers, S^., Dyble, M. and Migliano, A. B. (2019) Why so many Agta boys? Explaining extreme sex ratios in Philippine forgers. Evolutionary Human Sciences, 1: e5. ^joint first authors.
Abstract
Male-biased sex ratios have been observed in multiple small-scale societies. Although intentional and systematic female-biased mortality has been posited as an explanation, there is often a lack of ethnographic evidence of systematic female neglect and/or infanticide. The Agta, a foraging population from the Philippines, have a skewed sex ratio of 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smith D., et al. (2018) A Friend in Need is a Friend Indeed. Evolution and Human Behaviour.</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/15friend/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/15friend/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Smith D., Major, K., Dyble, M., Page, A.E., Migliano, A.B., Thompson, J., Chaudhary, N., Salali, G.D., Vinicius, L. and Mace, R. (2018) A Friend in Need is a Friend Indeed: Need-based sharing, rather than cooperative assortment, predicts experimental resource transfers among Agta hunter-gatherers. Evolution and Human Behaviour, doi.org/10.1016/j.evolhumbehav.2018.08.004.
Abstract
Despite much theorizing, the evolutionary reasons why humans cooperate extensively with unrelated individuals are still largely unknown. While reciprocity explains many instances of non-kin cooperation, much remains to be understood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Page, A. E., et al. (2018) Hunter-gatherer health and development policy. Social Science and Medicine.</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/14health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/14health/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Page, A. E., Minter, T., Viguier, S., and Migliano, A. B. (2018) Hunter-gatherer health and development policy: how the promotion of sedentism worsens the Agta’s health outcomes. Social Science and Medicine, 197: 39-48.
Abstract
Many hunter-gatherer groups live on the outskirts of wider society, experiencing poor health outcomes with little access to medical care. From a development perspective, key interventions include the sedentarisation of these mobile peoples into camps nearby larger towns with sanitation infrastructure and medical care, as increased access to services is assumed to improve outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smith, D., et al. (2017) Cooperation and the evolution of hunter-gatherer storytelling. Nature Communications.</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/16story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/16story/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Smith, D., Schlaepfer, P., Major, K., Dyble, M., Page, A.E., Thompson, J., Chaudhary, N., Salali, G.D., Mace, R., Vinicius, L., and Migliano, A.B. (2017) Cooperation and the evolution of hunter-gatherer storytelling. Nature Communications, 8 (1853): doi:10.1038/s41467-017-02036-8.
Abstract
Storytelling is a human universal. From gathering around the camp-fire telling tales of ancestors to watching the latest television box-set, humans are inveterate producers and consumers of stories. Despite its ubiquity, little attention has been given to understanding the function and evolution of storytelling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diekmann, Y., et al. (2017) Accurate age estimation in small-scale societies. PNAS</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/18age/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/18age/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Diekmann, Y., Smith, D., Gerbault, P., Dyble, M., Page, A.E., Chaudhary, N., Migliano, A.B., Thomas, M.G. (2017) Accurate age estimation in small-scale societies. PNAS, 114 (31): 8205-8210.
Abstract
Precise estimation of age is essential in evolutionary anthropology, especially to infer population age structures and understand the evolution of human life history diversity. However, in small-scale societies, such as hunter-gatherer populations, time is often not referred to in calendar years, and accurate age estimation remains a challenge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Page, A. E., et al. (2017) Hunter-Gatherer Social Networks and Reproductive Success. Scientific Reports</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/17hgnetwork/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/17hgnetwork/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Page, A. E., Chaudhary, N., Viguier, S., Dyble, M., Smith, D., Salali, G., Thompson, J., Mace, R., &amp;amp;Migliano, A.B. (2017) Hunter-Gatherer Social Networks and Reproductive Success. Scientific Reports, 7: 1153.
Abstract
Individuals’ centrality in their social network (who they and their social ties are connected to) has been associated with fertility, longevity, disease and information transmission in a range of taxa. Here, we present the first exploration in humans of the relationship between reproductive success and different measures of network centrality of 39 Agta and 38 BaYaka mothers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migliano, A.B., et al. (2017) Characterization of hunter-gatherer networks and implications for cumulative culture. Nature Human Behaviour</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/19cumcult/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/19cumcult/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Migliano, A.B., Page, A.E., Gómez-Gardeñes, J., Salali, G.D., Viguier, S., Dyble, M., Thompson, J., Chaudhary, N., Smith, D., Strods, J., Mace, R., Thomas, M.G., Latora, V., Vinicius, L., (2017) Characterization of hunter-gatherer networks and implications for cumulative culture. Nature Human Behaviour, 1: 1–6.
Abstract
Social networks in modern societies are highly structured, usually involving frequent contact with a small number of unrelated ‘friends’. However, contact network structures in traditional small-scale societies, especially hunter-gatherers, are poorly characterized.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Salali, G.D, et al. (2016) Knowledge-sharing networks in hunter-gatherers and the evolution of cumulative culture. Current Biology</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/22knowshare/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/22knowshare/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Salali, G.D., Chaudhary, N., Thompson, J., Grace, O.M., Burgt, X.M. van der, Dyble, M., Page, A.E., Smith, D., Lewis, J., Mace, R., Vinicius, L., Migliano, A.B. (2016) Knowledge-sharing networks in hunter-gatherers and the evolution of cumulative culture. Current Biology, 26 (18): 2516-2521.
Abstract
Humans possess the unique ability for cumulative culture. It has been argued that hunter-gatherer’s complex social structure has facilitated the evolution of cumulative culture by allowing information exchange among large pools of individuals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dyble, M., et al. (2016) Networks of food sharing reveal the functional significance of multilevel sociality in two hunter-gatherer groups. Current Biology</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/20multilevel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/20multilevel/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Dyble, M., Thompson, J., Page, A.E., Chaudhary, N., Salali, G.D., Vinicius, L., Mace, R., Migliano, A.B. (2016) Networks of food sharing reveal the functional significance of multilevel sociality in two hunter-gatherer groups. Current Biology, 26 (15): 2017-2021.
Abstract
Like many other mammalian and primate societies, humans are said to live in multilevel social groups, with individuals situated in a series of hierarchically structured sub-groups. Although this multilevel social organization has been described among contemporary hunter-gatherers, questions remain as to the benefits that individuals derive from living in such groups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chaudhary, N. et al. (2016) Within-Group Competition for Cooperation among BaYaka Hunter-Gatherers. Scientific Reports</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/24compcoop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/24compcoop/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Chaudhary, N., Salali, G., Thompson, J. Page, A. E., Smith, D., Dyble, M., Mace, R., and Migliano, A. (2016) Within-Group Competition for Cooperation among BaYaka Hunter-Gatherers. Scientific Reports, 6: 29120.
Abstract
Humans regularly cooperate with non-kin, which has been theorized to require reciprocity between repeatedly interacting and trusting individuals. However, the role of repeated interactions has not previously been demonstrated in explaining real-world patterns of hunter–gatherer cooperation. Here we explore cooperation among the Agta, a population of Filipino hunter–gatherers, using data from both actual resource transfers and two experimental games across multiple camps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smith, D. et al. (2016) Camp Stability Predicts Patterns of Hunter-Gatherer Cooperation. Royal Society Open Science</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/23stablity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/23stablity/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Smith, D., Dyble, M., Thompson, J., Major, K., Page, A. E., Chaudhary, N., Salali, G., Vinicius, L., Migliano, A. B. and Mace, R. (2016) Camp Stability Predicts Patterns of Hunter-Gatherer Cooperation. Royal Society Open Science, 3: 160131.
Abstract
Humans regularly cooperate with non-kin, which has been theorized to require reciprocity between repeatedly interacting and trusting individuals. However, the role of repeated interactions has not previously been demonstrated in explaining real-world patterns of hunter–gatherer cooperation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Page, A. E., et al. (2016) Reproductive trade-offs in extant hunter-gatherers suggest adaptive mechanism for the Neolithic expansion. PNAS</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/21tradeoff/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/21tradeoff/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Page, A. E., Viguier, S., Dyble, M., Smith, D., Chaudhary, N., Salali, G., Thompson, J., Vinicius, L., Mace, R., and Migliano, A. B. (2016) Reproductive trade-offs in extant hunter-gatherers suggest adaptive mechanism for the Neolithic expansion. PNAS, 113 (17): 4694-4699.
Abstract
The Neolithic demographic transition remains a paradox, because it is associated with both higher rates of population growth and increased morbidity and mortality rates. Here we reconcile the conflicting evidence by proposing that the spread of agriculture involved a life history quality–quantity trade-off whereby mothers traded offspring survival for increased fertility, achieving greater reproductive success despite deteriorating health.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chaudhary, N. et al. (2016) Polygyny without wealth: Popularity in gift games predicts polygyny in BaYaka Pygmies. Royal Society Open Science</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/26polygyny/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/26polygyny/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Chaudhary, N., Salali, G., Thompson, J., Dyble, M., Page, A. E., Smith, D., Mace, R., and Migliano, A. (2015) Polygyny without wealth: Popularity in gift games predicts polygyny in BaYaka Pygmies. Royal Society Open Science, 2: 150054.
Abstract
The occurrence of polygynous marriage in hunter–gatherer societies, which do not accumulate wealth, remains largely unexplored since resource availability is dependent on male hunting capacity and limited by the lack of storage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dyble, M. et al. (2016) Sex equality can explain the unique social structure of hunter-gatherer bands. Science</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/25sexequality/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/25sexequality/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Dyble, M., Salali, G., Chaudhary, N., Page, A. E, Thompson, J., Smith, D., Vinicius, L., Mace, R., and Migliano, A. (2015) Sex equality can explain the unique social structure of hunter-gatherer bands. Science, 348(6236): 796-8.
Abstract
The social organization of mobile hunter-gatherers has several derived features, including low within-camp relatedness and fluid meta-groups. Although these features have been proposed to have provided the selective context for the evolution of human hypercooperation and cumulative culture, how such a distinctive social system may have emerged remains unclear.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
