<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reproductive success on Abigail E. Page</title>
    <link>https://abbeyepage.com/tags/reproductive-success/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reproductive success on Abigail E. Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://abbeyepage.com/tags/reproductive-success/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Page, A. E., et al. (2017) Hunter-Gatherer Social Networks and Reproductive Success. Scientific Reports</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/17hgnetwork/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/17hgnetwork/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Page, A. E., Chaudhary, N., Viguier, S., Dyble, M., Smith, D., Salali, G., Thompson, J., Mace, R., &amp;amp;Migliano, A.B. (2017) Hunter-Gatherer Social Networks and Reproductive Success. Scientific Reports, 7: 1153.
Abstract
Individuals’ centrality in their social network (who they and their social ties are connected to) has been associated with fertility, longevity, disease and information transmission in a range of taxa. Here, we present the first exploration in humans of the relationship between reproductive success and different measures of network centrality of 39 Agta and 38 BaYaka mothers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Page, A. E., et al. (2016) Reproductive trade-offs in extant hunter-gatherers suggest adaptive mechanism for the Neolithic expansion. PNAS</title>
      <link>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/21tradeoff/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abbeyepage.com/publications/21tradeoff/</guid>
      <description>Citation
Page, A. E., Viguier, S., Dyble, M., Smith, D., Chaudhary, N., Salali, G., Thompson, J., Vinicius, L., Mace, R., and Migliano, A. B. (2016) Reproductive trade-offs in extant hunter-gatherers suggest adaptive mechanism for the Neolithic expansion. PNAS, 113 (17): 4694-4699.
Abstract
The Neolithic demographic transition remains a paradox, because it is associated with both higher rates of population growth and increased morbidity and mortality rates. Here we reconcile the conflicting evidence by proposing that the spread of agriculture involved a life history quality–quantity trade-off whereby mothers traded offspring survival for increased fertility, achieving greater reproductive success despite deteriorating health.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
